A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office of the Director, Office Files of Alice Allen and Lloyd Garrison FA635
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office of the Director, Office Files of Alice Allen and Lloyd Garrison
1980-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Allen, Alice
Garrison, Lloyd
Ford Foundation
FA635
6.57 Cubic Feet 5 record storage boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, and press logs.
Arrangement
As received.
Biographical / Historical
Alice Allen worked as a Senior Advisor in the Ford Foundation's Office of Communications.
Biographical / Historical
Lloyd McKim Garrison (1931-2014) was a journalist who, from 1991 to 1995, served as Director of the Ford Foundation's Office of Communications. Garrison left the Office of Communications to work on the Ford Foundation History Project which was intended to generate an authorized history of the Foundation from 1980 to 1995 (Ford Foundation records, Ford Foundation History Project (FA251).
Garrison's pre-Ford Foundation journalism career encompassed positions in radio, TV, and print media. He was a news writer at NBC News and then he worked at the New York Times where he covered Europe and Africa. Later, he was a staff writer at Time Magazine and started a bimonthly magazine for the United Nations Development Program.
Garrison was a great-great-grandson of William Lloyd Garrison, abolitionist and founder of the anti-slavery newspaper, the Liberator. His father Lloyd K. Garrison was President of the New York City Board of Education from 1961 to 1967, preceding the decentralization of the city's public school system. Lloyd K. Garrison served on the Mayor's Advisory Panel on Decentralization chaired by Ford Foundation President McGeorge Bundy for a week before leaving the Board of Education in 1967 (Ford Foundation records, New York City Decentralization of Schools (FA1524)).
During his retirement, Garrison founded the Norfolk Now newspaper in Norfolk, Connecticut where he lived. Garrison died in 2014.
- Thomas, Franklin A, 1995 (Box 1)
- Asia Programs, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Office of Communications Staff Reports, 1995 (Box 1)
- United Nations (UNA-UN), 1995 (Box 1)
- Allen, Alice (Miscellaneous Files), 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Re-Linking Study, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Disks
- Miscellaneous, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Fax to Alice Allen -- Various, 1995 (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1981 (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1982 (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1990 (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 January (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 February (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 March (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 April (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 May (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 June (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 July (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 August (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 September (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 October (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 November (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1994 December (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 January (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 February (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 March (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 April (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 May (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 June (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 July (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 August (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 September (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 October (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 November (Box 1)
- Press Log, 1995 December (Box 1)
- Social Investing, 1990 (Box 2)
- Race Relations/Campus Diversity Meeting, 1990 July 2 (Box 2)
- United Nations Study -- Press Briefing, 1991 (Box 2)
- Black and Hispanic Museums, 1990 September 20 (Box 2)
- Project Status -- Office of Communications, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- Media Initiative, 1990 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- Publications -- General Memoranda and Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2)
- Office of Reports -- General Memoranda and Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- Media/General (Press), 1989-1990 (Box 2)
- BBC World Service -- Leslie Stone/Alastair Osborne, 1990 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- Communications Seminar, 1989 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- Projected Work with Office of Communications FY 1990 (Box 2)
- Office of Reports -- Changing Relations -- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- Social Welfare -- The Common Good -- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2)
- Office of Communications -- General Information, 1988-1992 (Box 3)
  Disk
- Miscellaneous, 1995 (Box 3)
- Thomas, Franklin, 1996 (Box 3)
- Partnership for National Service (Americorps), 1995 (Box 3)
- Correspondence Control, 1992 (Box 3)
- Media Workshop for Grantees, 1991 (Box 3)
- Biographies, circa 1995 (Box 3)
- Office of Communications -- Chronological Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
- Immigrant Student Program, 1989 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Immigration -- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Immigration -- Grant Recommendations, 1987-1988 (Box 3)
- Ford Foundation Letter, 1991 (Box 3)
- Office of Communications -- Innovating America, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
- Office of Communications -- Innovations, 1990 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Innovations -- Award Recipients, 1987 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Innovations -- Ford Foundation News Releases, 1987 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Innovations -- Notes, 1987 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Innovations -- Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 3)
  Slides
- Office of Reports -- Innovations -- Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- International Organizations -- Drafts, 1986 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- International Organizations -- Related Grant Actions, 1985 (Box 3)
- Office of Reports -- Urquhard, Brian -- Iran-Iraq War Conference, 1987 April 21-22 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Urquhard, Brian -- Interviews, 1986 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Urquhard, Brian -- Articles, 1980-1987 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Urquhard, Brian -- Foundation-Administered Project, 1987 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Urquhard, Brian -- Biography, 1985 October (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Urquhard, Brian -- Reception -- Correspondence, 1987 November 12 (Box 4)
- Minority Museums, 1987-1989 (Box 4)
- Office of Communications -- United Nations Leadership Study -- Program Paper, 1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Communications -- United Nations Leadership Study -- Press Release, 1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Communications -- United Nations Leadership Study -- Media, 1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Communications -- United Nations Leadership Study -- Distribution, 1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Communications -- United Nations Leadership Study -- Grant Actions, 1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Mission/Activities, 1989 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Miscellaneous, 1966-1988 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Office of Reports, 1978 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Poor Support -- Correspondence, 1988 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Poor Support -- Grant Actions, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Poor Support -- Notes, 1988 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Women's Program Forum -- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- National Commission on Testing and Public Policy, 1989 (Box 4)
- Rural Poverty, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
- Race Relations/Campus Diversity, 1990 September (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Staff -- General Memoranda, 1984-1992 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Publications -- Comments/Suggestions, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Publications -- Foundation-Assisted Program, 1991 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Publications -- Distribution, 1987-1990 (Box 4)
- Office of Reports -- Publications -- Notes, 1987 (Box 4)
- Office of Communications -- QUASAR Project -- Grant Action, 1989 (Box 5)
- Office of Communications -- QUASAR Project -- Project Summary, 1989 (Box 5)
- Office of Communications -- QUASAR Project -- Press Conference, 1989 (Box 5)
  Video Cassette
- Office of Communications -- QUASAR Project -- General, 1989 (Box 5)
- Office of Communications -- Race Relations/Campus Diversity -- Correspondence/Memoranda, 1990 (Box 5)
- Office of Communications -- Race Relations/Campus Diversity -- Diversity Grantees, 1990 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- International Organizations and Law, 1988-1990 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation -- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation -- Grant Actions, 1988 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation -- Organizational Information, 1990 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Manpower Demonstration Research Corporation -- Notes, 1990 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Kelleher, Catherine -- Interviews, 1988 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Kelleher, Catherine -- Grant Actions, 1988 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- Kelleher, Catherine -- Profile and Proposal, 1987 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- South Africa Series -- General, 1990 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- South Africa Series -- Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5)
- Office of Reports -- South Africa Series -- Drafts, 1988 (Box 5)
- Social Welfare -- Clippings, 1989 (Box 5)
- Social Welfare -- General, 1989 (Box 5)
- Office of Communications -- Soviet-East European Study Group -- Ford Foundation Conference on Czechoslovakia, 1990 January 4 (Box 5)
- Office of Communications -- Soviet-East European Study Group -- Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 5)
- Ford Foundation -- General Information, 1988-1989 (Box 5)
- Ford Foundation -- Organization, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
- Ford Foundation -- Senegal (West Africa) -- Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous Reports, 1990 (Box 5)